Hey, everyone!
Good to see you, Cap!
Friede!
Thanks for inviting us along today!
I can’t wait to do fieldwork!
I wonder what Pokémon we’ll find!
What’re you doin’?
E-Err... Umm...
You’re the newbie I’ve been hearing about?
I’m Friede. Nice to meet you!
N-N-N-Navi!
O-Ohh!
I’m so happy to meet the founding leader
and Pokémon Professor!
Well, you’re energetic!
Just the sort of trainer for the Rising Voltteccers!
Right!
So that’s your partner, Navi?
Yep! This is Metamon!
So, you can get nervous too, eh?
Little kids should shut it!
Navi’s been looking forward
to meeting you.
Don’t tell him!
Well then, should we get going?
Oh, we don’t have a full group yet.
Huh?
Didn’t I mention?
Another professor is joining us today.
Friede!
Ooh! Let me introduce you!
This is Professor Willow!
Go on a journey
looking for Pokémon!
Ready, set, and... GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Put our palms together, raise them high, and let our lights unite
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
In rain, gales, or even blizzards
We can laugh together as friends
All of the gaps in the Index
let’s fill them in bit by bit
If you’re trying to be someone else
Don’t think like that
You’re fine just as you are
Don’t lose yourself
Recollect on what’s in your pocket
This is what makes us strong
A heartfelt bond that will never fade
Ready, set, and...
GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Let’s fly, higher and higher!
It’s fine to make mistakes
just rest your wings
When you’ve caught your breath
you can fly off once more!
Come along with us, oh-oh
Voltteccers
Pass the endlessly turning seasons,
and venture into brand-new skies
The Expanding World, I'll GO With You!
Cap! That hat still looks good on you!
Long time no see, Professor Willow.
Yeah, glad to see
you’re still hard at work.
So, you’re the Rising Voltteccers?
I hear you’ve traveled the world
and seen lots of different Pokémon.
I’m excited to have the chance
to do research with you!
Professor Willow travels the world
surveying Pokémon ecology and distribution.
Look! What’s that over there?
Ooh! That’s rare!
Research time!
Huh?!
I think Professor Willow and Friede
might have a lot in common...
Huh? What’s this thing?
A PokéStop.
They’re installed around here
to aid in the research of Pokémon.
For research?
Whoa! Something popped out!
Monster Balls, and berries too!
Mega-innerestin’! Lemme try!
And that’s not all!
If you use this Lure Module,
nearby Pokémon will gather around.
Wow, it’s true!
Go and research what Pokémon live here,
especially in the vicinity of the PokéStops!
A forested area, and...
a beach further out, huh?
Grab their attention with berries,
toss balls, and catch them.
I’ll look after the Pokémon you find!
Awright!
Lessee who can catch the most!
Navi won’t lose!
Finding a variety of species
will give us a picture of this area’s distribution.
Mm-hmm.
Let the research begin!
Okay!
A Nonokurage, huh?
You’re gonna be mine!
Darn it!
Ult! You have to grab
their attention with berries first!
That’s a pain!
I don’t need nunna that...
Aim for the head.
Okay, Master!
How come?!
Your target is a living thing!
Don’t expect it to be easy.
I know that! One more time!
Ah!
Aw man, I used ‘em all!
Yamirami!
Time to refill at a PokéStop!
What’re you doin’?
This PokéStop won’t turn!
What’s that?
A Pokémon!
Kakuleon. Color Change Pokémon.
Normal type.
It changes its hue
to blend into its surroundings.
The zigzag pattern on its belly
remains unchanged.
Ooh...
Kakuleon often hide on PokéStops.
Innerestin’! Lemme—!
Oh no!
Just stay outta my way next time!
S-Sorry...
Nice!
Great!
All right!
A Yareyutan, huh?
That’s a big find.
It could be the boss of this area.
It won’t eat my berries.
How about some Golden Zuri Berries?
Ooh!
Now!
In that case!
So close!
Loudbone!
Excellent!
Great teamwork!
I get it... Then maybe if I have Mega Yamirami
deflect it with the gem...
Huh?
All right! Time to hit the beach?
Waaah!
What’s all this?!
It’s full of Shellder...
It seems that there’s
a mass outbreak of them...
I’ll get one this time.
First, give it a Zuri Berry...
Awright!
Wha—?!
Get back here!
Ooh!
It evolved?!
Amazing!
Maybe all those Shellder
are here to look for Yadon.
Ahh! Metamon is evolving!
Huh?
Now! Go!
Excellent!
Yay!
Good going, Navi!
Congrats!
I ain’t givin’ up yet!
Metamon, let’s go look over there!
An Umidigda!
They’re a rare sight around here!
That’s a nice rhythm!
Let’s sing, Loudbone!
Now’s your chance, Liko!
Yeah!
Excellent!
Huh?
What Pokémon is it this time...?
Hyah!
Waah!
Wah!
I’m sorr—!
You wanna catch that Yayakoma?
Yeah.
So I’m waiting for a chance to—
It spotted me!
Hyah!
Ahh!
Aww... That was my chance
to become a trainer...
So you don’t have any Pokémon yet...?
Ooh! Well then, Navi-senpai here
has got a ton to teach ya!
Like what?
Like... lemme see...
How to toss Monster Balls!
Just watch me...
Hyah!
You... You’re pretty funny!
The name’s not “you,” it’s Navi!
This’s my partner, Metamon.
I’m Gota. I live in a town nearby.
Navi...?
Yes, I see.
You, an aspiring Pokémon Trainer,
wanna catch your first Pokémon.
Awright! Then as your senpai,
I’ve got a ton to teach—
Ult, Navi did that already.
Huh?
How am I supposed to
catch a Yayakoma...?
Don’t fret over it.
A catch is a twist of fate.
Your first Pokémon
is bound to come to you!
Really?
You never know when it might be,
or if this one’s the one...
But I’m sure your passion
will get through to it!
Thanks to all of you,
I’m getting a good idea of the distribution here!
It’s intriguing that this area is home
to such a diverse mix of Pokémon!
If I were to guess why, since this area’s the border between
the forest and the sea, some Pokémon ecologies...
What’s wrong?
Think Gota managed to catch one?
I want him to meet the perfect partner,
like how Navi met Metamon!
Master said it, right?
A catch is a twist of fate!
Not worth fretting over.
Right, Master?
Yeah. When the time comes,
the Pokémon will find you.
So the same happened to you, Friede?
Back when I was smaller than all of you.
A Pokémon Professor’s first Pokémon!
Just how did you meet Lizardon?
I’m mega-curious!
How we met...
Well, that was...
Good morning, everyone!
Let’s make today another—
Good morning!
Friede! Late again?
I made it, didn’t I?
I’m safe, right, Ms. Lucca?
If you were running in the hall,
you’re out.
Ahh...
Great, right? This is my Caterpie!
I caught it in the forest!
Well, my dad promised
me he’d get me a Guardie!
Seriously?!
I wanna get my own Pokémon soon, too...
Look at this!
I put a ribbon on my Purin!
So cute!
Oh right, did you hear?
They say someone in the next class caught a Pikachu!
By my calculations,
it should’ve worked...
Practicing again this morning?
Whatcha want, Orio?
You were late.
I said I was safe.
I’m so close to getting this to work!
Always with that...
Is making airplanes
really that much fun?
Yeah! Thinking about being able to fly
gets me so psyched!
Orio! You should try it too!
Eh... If I feel like it.
More importantly, Friede...
Have you picked your first Pokémon?
Not interested.
You don’t want to be a trainer?
Not when my dream’s to be a pilot!
Soon as I can, bam!
I wanna be flying!
That’s it!
If I make the wings this size,
the air resistance will...
Back then, I was always on my own,
devoted to my dream.
I was sure that was gonna work...
I’m not giving up!
I’ll find a way to fly!
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
Here goes nothing!
All right! A new record!
Huh?
Did you see that? I was flying!
Cool, huh?!
Although, well...
I only flew for a little...
What is it?
Whoa!
Waah!
My goggles!
Stop!
Where did that guy go?
Not it.
You can fly...
That makes you my senpai.
Ah, just you...?
Sure is gutsy for such a little guy.
So this is where they live...
I live so close by to them,
but I don’t know a thing about them.
So there’s all kinds of
different Pokémon...
Right, the one with my goggles!
Found you!
You okay?!
That guy...
It’s copying me.
You’ve got an eye
for the sky too, huh?
But those goggles...
My dad bought them for me.
Let’s fly together!
I wanna fly too!
We’ve both got the same dream!
Let’s head for the sky together!
Ooh, so you made friends
with a Hitokage.
So it’s called a Hitokage?
You didn’t even know its name?
I don’t know much about Pokémon.
You can start now.
Being with them is what
allows your world to expand.
My world...
Let’s be great friends, Hitokage!
Congrats on the catch, Friede-kun.
I caught Hitokage,
and that expanded my world.
We headed to all kinds of different places,
and met all kinds of different Pokémon.
I became devoted to Pokémon.
My partner immersed me
in their world.
Hitokage evolved...
...and grew...
...until finally,
we got to fly together!
Yahoo!
Somewhere along the line,
I set my sights on being a Pokémon Professor.
Congrats!
We expect good things from you!
Thank you very much!
Which is how I ended up stepping out
into a world of adventures with Lizardon.
So that’s how the two of you met!
Lovely!
Oh, no!
There’s still one area
we haven’t surveyed!
Let’s head off to research it quick!
Huh?!
I was thinking it was about time
to make dinner...
Well then, how about we work up
a bit more appetite before sundown?
I can’t quit now!
Awright! I’m mega-fired up!
Good morning!
You really put in some good
surveying work yesterday!
All of you, thank you!
Thank you! Thank you!
And thank you very much, too!
It was mega-fun!
Please invite us along again!
Ahh!
Go—!
Just watch.
All right!
Gota, congrats!
Navi! Thank you!
Excellent!
Now you, too, are a Pokémon Trainer!
Incredible adventures await you!
Right!
See you, then!
Until we meet again!
Bye-bye!
They said they were heading right off
to do some new research.
That’s some stamina...
They’re always so devoted.
So’re all of us, right?!
Let’s go see some new Pokémon!
Yeah!
Wait for us!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Friede here!
It’s time to Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie!
Today’s topic is Hitokage!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Hitokage
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Lizard Pokémon
Fire
Blaze
The flame on its tail
is a display of its life force.
Something can be discerned via this flame,
but do you know what it is?
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Feelings
The future
The truth
See the answer after the commercials!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Gonna give my motivation button a little tap!
The power of hard work is amazing!
(Ahem!)
But if I slack off I might end up devolving...
Well, that’s no good!
But now you mention it...
I know button mashing won’t help at all
So stop shaking this maiden’s heart already
(Stop it!)
Getting attached, but then they turn away
When things just don’t go the way that you want...
Isn’t it so fun? Doesn’t it make your heart race?
Doesn’t it make you all excited?
When I feel a spark...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
Face to face with the dream I’ve always imagined...
I’ve got electric jolts running through me!
I’m so lovey-dovey I can’t even move!
When I know change is still inside of me...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
then we can be together forever
We’ll conquer any obstacle!
I know our future will shine!
So let’s be friends!
Pick up you! I want you! Hit chu straight in the heart!
Pick up you! I want you! We’re right at the peak of our adven-chu!!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Time to announce
the correct answer!
The answer is...
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
Feelings
The future
The truth
A: Feelings!
Feelings
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
The flame on its tail
displays its feelings.
When it’s emotional,
it blazes up fiercely!
That was a great Ember, huh?
Let’s train some more,
and make sure we win next time!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Next episode
It’s a festival!
I’m gonna wear a cute jinbei,
and do lots of ring tossing and yo-yo fishing!
Oh, and eat candy apples too!
Next episode
So, this is your first
Kitakami hamlet festival, Navi?
I bet you can’t wait!
Yup!
Huh? Is that a kid from the village?
Hi! Wanna come with us?
Next episode
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters!
Navi and the Mysterious Masked Child
Wait, “Masked Child”?